Tufts Daily UP029
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Tufts Daily, 2001; UP029.022; 4.8 Linear Feet
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 09; UP029.022.035.00018 (Volume Shared 134)
    IR [International Relations], economics majors see rising popularity. Award ceremony opens Kids' Day. Economist address unemployment. Lehrer making rare college appearance. Online registration: a luxury or a problem?, Dealing with advisors needn't change. Info in the palm of your hand - TuftsLife goes mobile. King Solomon conquers the crowd at Hotung, Brother Ezra rounds out royal family. Softball takes two over Bates in weekend doubleheader. Jumbos tip Purple Cows for important conference win, Win over Williams first over the last six years. Five goal spurt spoils potential upset over Williams. Jumbos, Cardinals split four games in busy weekend.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 10; UP029.022.035.00019 (Volume Shared 134)
    Israelis culpable for Middle East violence, Jewish journalist says. Students, senators appear apathetic about TCU [Tufts Community Union] Senate-wide non-election. An insider's look at Tufts from an outsider's perspective. MIT [Massachusetts Institute of Technology] to release course material on Internet, Does Tufts CourseInfo compare? Voice of a Baby - the rise of a Church. Men's trackl opens season with fast start. Freshman pitcher Randy Newsom engineers convincing win versus MIT [Massachusetts Institute of Technology], Ayres drives in six runs in Tufts' 11-1 blowout victory. Men's crew battles rocky waters, women cruise in race. Viewpoints: An immodest proposal, The next victims, Mexico: Change in sight.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 11; UP029.022.035.00020 (Volume Shared 134)
    Few students left without rooms in housing lottery. Dining Services to reorganize managerial structure next year. Jewish activists spread Ladino culture at Tufts. Professors in the News: Tufts professors comment on US-China conflict, Gene influences alcohol's apparent health benefits, says Tufts expert, Child development professor highlights danger of parental selfishness. Outwit, outplay, outlast, Junior sets up his camp on library roof. When did I get old? Women's track battles Division I schools, bad weather. Moreau, Drake reach milestones in softball careers over weekend. Three riders qualify for Zone Championships. On Air and Zones and Answers.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 12; UP029.022.035.00021 (Volume Shared 134)
    Offensive message on cannon covered up by Tufts Facilities. Similar platforms blur lines between hopeful TCU [Tufts Community Union] presidential candidates. Searching for a bond, TCF [Tufts Christian Fellowship] and TTLGBC [Tufts Transgendered, Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Collective] co-host lecture. Tufts grad schools keep up with nation's best. Seeking alternatives, Health Services, Planned Parenthood provide options to pregnant students. Looking at campus crime, University provides safety for students. Religion joins social life, faith, Why do some services attract more students? Herbert leads streaking Jumbos into heart of conference schedule. Tufts sailing brings home win in Friis Cup. Jumbos can't scratch Panthers, Early run by Middlebury dooms Jumbos, now 5-4. Men's V-ball unable to repeat NE success, Seniors lead team to Nationals. Viewpoints: 'West Side Story' stereotypes Puerto Ricans, The spirit of Shabbat, My ballot, Take charge of your careers, Misunderstood words. Editorial: Culture reps should not get full voting rights. Best of Tufts.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 17; UP029.022.035.00023 (Volume Shared 134)
    Shelton, Greenberg nominated for TCU [Tufts Community Union] presidency. Former Sec. Richardson considered to replace the departing DiBiaggio, Interviewed by committee, but prospects seem unlikely. Baseball team sweeps weekend series. Sun sets on president Moon's year in office. Student escorts available late-night. Bhangra blows up DC, New Indian dance team impressive. 'Radix' a new liberal alternative, Leftist mag coming soon to a campus building near you. Panelists debate role of the IMF [International Monetary Fund]. Mystic River Awareness Week highlights environmental problems. World Civ. requirement unlikely to see change. The people in my neighborhood. Aliens to hit the arena theater, 'Tales of the Lost Formicans' opens tonight at Balch. Men's lacrosse ruches Colby White Mules for 8-4 win. Strong Colby win after tough Middlebury loss. Women's softball sweeps twinbill from Amherst. Viewpoints: Save Falun Gong, Speaking truth, Convergence, No sense in censorship, The end of an era.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 18; UP029.022.035.00024 (Volume Shared 134)
    Tufts' reputation strong despite 'Wall Street Journal' snub. Dining Services to upgrade problematic points machines. Engineers win environmental design contest. Grad School News: Tufts researchers find that herbal remedies interfere with other drugs, Med School faculty honored with endowed chairs, Graduate School Council to host charity 'Fun Run'. Jumbo marathoner takes on Boston, New England. Tufts program promotes teh college experience, Urban Outreach Institute gives high schoolers a glimpse of campus life. There's no business... Red-hot softball team has won eight of last nine games. Men's track finishes second at Bowdoin Hezagonal, MIT [Massachusetts Institute of Technology] first. Men's crew lands rare regular-season victory over UNH [University of New Hampshire]. Trahan, Callahan garner NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] Player of the Week honors.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 19; UP029.022.035.00025 (Volume Shared 134)
    Harvard students stage sit-in, demand wage increase for university employees. Then there were (about) ten, List confidential, Bernstein not among candidates. Hillel sponsers week-long Holocaust commemoration. Harvard hires Prof. Bose, Tufts' expert on South Asia. Pre-frosh share Tufts' experience, Many say their overnight visit affects college decision. Win at Babson puts end to Jumbos' four-game losing streak. Women's sailing finishes second at the Dellenbaugh Trophy race. Women's lacrosse team nearly upsets its rival, Amherst Lord Jeffs. Despite injuries, women's track team excels at Springfield. Viewpoints: Big names worth the wait, Anotehr look at the conflict, China got lost in mid-air, Reconnecting with the people, Senate working hard, but not hard enough, An unjust amendment, Save new TCU [Tufts Community Union] constitution, kill culture rep. amendment, Every vote counts.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 23; UP029.022.035.00026 (Volume Shared 134)
    Poll projects Greenberg victory. Elections for TCUJ [Tufts Community Union Judiciary], CSL [Committee on Student Life]go uncontested. TSR [Tufts Student Resources] tightens finances to improve efficiency. Panelists say that environmental justice a human, civil rights issue. PAA [Pan African Alliance] to investigate minority faculty retention problems. Students speak out about women's magazines, Stereotypes, self-esteem cited as concerns. Why 'Maxim' has changed everything, Will men's magazines ever be the same? Wmfo's Mikey Dee, Godsmack big winners at BMAs [Boston Music Awards]. Tufts Dance Collective shows audience a good time, Hip-hop, breakdancing, and more. 'Daily Show's' dynamic Black brings his humor to Tufts. Strong pitching propels softball in Tufts Invitational. Baseball, softball teams leading NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] going into final week. Baseball take two of three from Colby. Men's lacrosse falls to Bates 11-10 in overtime thriller.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 24; UP029.022.035.00027 (Volume Shared 134)
    Quesitons remain over removal of chalkings. Presidential candidates square off. At Harvard, PSLM [Progressive Student Labor Movement] still sitting, Administration refusing to negotiate with protesters. Seniors receive honors from alumni association. Tae kwon-do team brings Tuft's martial arts on the road. Saying goodbye. TSO [Tufts Student Orchestra] and guests play Cousens, Impressive orchestal performance of 'Resurrection'. Missing runners, men's track still finishes second at weekend meet. Crew program falls to tough competition, But women's lightweight places first. Women's lacrosse gets needed win, Wins in final two games would ensure playoff berth. Viewpoints: The use and misuse of grammar, Conflict of interest, Does Tufts have issues with its sexuality?
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 25; UP029.022.035.00028 (Volume Shared 134)
    Controversy erupts over TCU [Tufts Community Union] constitutional referendum, Vote will not be counted until after TCUJ [Tufts Community Union Judiciary] hearing. Economics department continues to struggle with understaffing, Two new hires for fall semester may ease tension. UCCPS [University College of Citizenship and Public Service] announces grant opportunites. University chaplain appointment postponed. Professors in the News: Tufts expert in favor of clinical drug trials on children, Milne says pharmaceutical companies' lawsuit against South Africa is risky, Tufts professor a vocal opponent to new antibacterial cleansing products, China conflict a mark of repeated history: Fletcher professor says. Plling the plug on the Internet, Tufts launches pilot to expand on wireless possibilities. MUTT [Multicultural Union at Tufts] helps mix things up, Multicultural students find home in new club. Tufts' religious history, Founded by Universalists, but what now? Fight the future. Editorial: Shelton the better option, Vote 'yes' on culture reps. Women's tennis team upset over NESCAC [Northeast Association of Schools and Colleges] Championship reults. Women's track leads pack at Connecticut College. Lacrosse teams face must-win situations against Wesleyan squads. A farewell column.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 April 30; UP029.022.035.00029 (Volume Shared 134)
    Content Warning
    The description of this issue includes a listing of headlines found in the issue. One of the headlines contains an anti-Black slur. The slur is censored. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
    Senate elects internal officers, Carson wins VP spot, Lee moves to treasury. Flinging towards finals. Funding problems delay new music facility initiative. Deans Fawaz and Hollister to step down next semester. Door opens up at Harvard, Administration will talk, but only if sit-in stops. Senators honor 'professors of the year'. Thinking outside the box, Hype! mime troupe combines tradition with innovation. Literary crimes at Tufts, Alumnus Golden takes students on a tour of his 'murder scenes'. Poll worker skulldruggery no problem. Viewpoints: What is at the end of a Tuftonian rainbow?, Fighting anti-queer language, F*cking N****r. Frisbee team gaining momentum en route to regionals. Semester in Review: Rumors Daily site shuts down, Snow storm causes cancellation of classes, Committee hopes to choose new president by semester's end, Administration begins testing new block schedule, Censorship allegations smear campus, canon, All TCU [Tufts Community Union] representatives chosen without election, After two years, fate of TCU [Tufts Community Union] constitution still unclear, Tufts' social life stages a comeback, Student's have dialogue on Arab-Isreali conflict, Trustees approve tenative plans to build new dorm, Hilfiger among notable speakers to visit Tufts. Pennant fever grips Hill, Baseball team takes to of three games to clinch NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] East title. Softball team to host NESCAC [New England Schools and Colleges Athletic Conference] tournament. Jumbos split with Polar Bears, Team secures home field advantage for tournament (softball). Men's lacrosse qualifies for playoffs despite weekend loss. Jumbos score 15 against Camels (women's lacrosse).
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 August 29; UP029.022.036.00001 (Volume 36)
    Al Gore to speak at Tufts; Bacow set for presidency; Diversity remains Tufts' top priority in choosing new class; University focuses on unity in this year's orientation programming; I.O. or: How I learned to snog; America's college town gearing up for another year; Students groups offer a variety of options; Soccer set to defend second-place finish in national tournament; Experienced players key in team's effort to improve on 2-6 record [Football]; Co-ed sailing brings home national championship.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 04; UP029.022.036.00002 (Volume 36)
    Bacow officially new president; Hip-hop group the Beatnuts to headline fall fest on Saturday; Mel Bernstein leaves Tufts after ten years; Summer shutdown of insecure Telnet frustrates students; Gore speech will focus on families; Mail services gets a technological facelift; But it home late-night for a buck; Tufts janitors deserve a fair shake; Moonwalking; Climbing the hill; Jolly good time for men's soccer team while in UK; Team hopes for net gain [Field Hockey].
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 06; UP029.022.036.00003 (Volume 36)
    Students, faculty consider life without the V.P. post; Drug, alcohol penalites are weakened; TU website revamped to improve navigation; Renovations improve looks, safety of Tufts; Students call janitors underpaid; Kosher meal plan starved for students; JumboFob zaps students into South hall. Farewell for a friend [Bob Asch]; Just what do you do as president anyway?; DiBiaggio leaves his mark on Tufts; TCCS has little regard for students needs; Don't be neutral! [S.L.A.M.]; Boston venues thrive with hundreds of acts, concerts; Harriers start season with higher expectations, ambitions [Men's cross country]; Samko's offense coming together [Football]; Sounds of the Red Sox choking is echoing through New England.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 10; UP029.022.036.00004 (Volume 36)
    Dibiaggio moves to Bendetson Hall, Boston office not available; Medford police dept. threatens Dall fest; Seven admissions afficers resign; Tufts rises one spot to 28; Medical schoopl raning up four spots in 'US News' list; For optimum health, follow the rainbow to a pot of vegetables; Students flock to substance free housing seeking calm; Turning trash to treasure; Music, food, and law for the masses at Fall Fest 2001; Women's soccer shocked in season opener; Split squad comes in fourth in home race [Men's cross country]; Runner's place third in first meet [Women's cross country].
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 12; UP029.022.036.00005 (Volume 36)
    Terror stikes New York, DC; Campus sobered by attack on America; Speakers stress need for strength, unity at chaplanicy-led service; Sprinklers installed in three more dorms during summer vacation; Midnight music behind Miller hall; Professors react with caution; Counseling center increases support network; A time for compassion; Support eachother despite diversity; A prayer in time of confusion; Women up to the challenge [soccer]; Top-ranked team calm despite pressure, loss [Women's soccer].
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 14; UP029.022.036.00006 (Volume 36)
    Hijacking suspects rae identified as American cope with attack; Gore puts off planned Tufts visit; Tufts-in-Ghana to be reviewed under new program advisor; Students faculty seek answers at forum led by [Sol] Gittleman, [Charles] Inouye; Blood donors from Tufts, entire nation are told to hold off; Tufts earns federal grant money for study of shrimp aquaculture; New campus center information monitor; Men have high goals for 2001 [Men's soccer]; Team burns Lasers in season opener [Men's soccer]; Women earn 2-0 win in NESCAC opener [Women's soccer]; Volleyball looks to build on last year's foundation, win 20 games.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 17; UP029.022.036.00007 (Volume 36)
    No meetings yet, but Senate hard at work; Professors say US should avoid quick fix solutions to terrorism; Spring '02 deadline set for music building; How to muscle up, slim down by improving your workout and diet; Travel plans changing in wake of attacks to New York; Attacks alter students' plans for Rosh Hashanah; Bookstore comes under new management; Beware of nationalism; A tale of two halves [Women's soccer]; Women triumph 3-1 in key NESCAC game [women's soccer]; Middleebury sneaks by in double overtime, 3-2, in NESCAC opener [men's soccer]; Team drops first two in close, tough games [field hockey].
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 18; UP029.022.036.00008 (Volume 36)
    Despite grief, deadlines continue; University switches DC lobbying firms; Study shows alcohol use at Tufts consistent with similiar sized schools; Freshmen exposed to dorm hate incident; Tragedy sparks hate crimes; Students who study abroad will now face new challenges; Ever ask a zombie to take you to the prom?; Men's cross country places second in UMass-Dartmouth Invitational; Women's volleyball 3-1 in first NESCAC weekend of season; Back to business for football team; Why Pakistan?; Tufts janitors, Tufts' injustice; Dear family; Watching the light; Loss of innocence.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 19; UP029.022.036.00009 (Volume 36)
    University negotiating purchase of abandoned school on Capen Street; Intersection upgrade delayed until spring; Sen. Kerry addresses anti-Muslim sentiments during speech at Tufts; MOPS [merchants on points] seeking fourth restaurant after loss of Urban Gourmet; New coffee shop patio opens; Bridgewater scholarship aids estranged LGBT [Lesbian, guy, bisexual, trans-gendered] students; Lewis Hall's best kept secret has something for everyone; [Micheal] Lambert's view is simpleminded; No drinking needed for Mountainclub membership; Women's soccer to butt heads with Conn. College Camles today; Around the conference in hockey [field hockey]; NESCAC Roundup, women's soccer style; Men's soccer set for battle with cross-town rival MIT Engineers; Third place is better than 'Fore' (golf team]; Cross country team has weekend off after cancellation of meet [women's cross country].
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 20; UP029.022.036.00010 (Volume 36)
    University police ease enforcement; Medford asks Tufts to turn down the music; TCU elections go online; University searching for new telephone, cable TV provider; Second-half surge leads TU over MIT; Lighting up Camels, Tufts wins 3rd straight [Women's soccer]; Sailing prepars to defend Hood Trophy this weekend; New York state of mind; A cataclysm or a prelude?; Scapegoat; From Burning to Brandishing.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 21; UP029.022.036.00011 (Volume 36)
    Still no name or donor for new Psych. facility; Pres. Bush asks congress, US to back 'lengthy' armed campaign; AOL demands anti-spam restrictions for Tufts e-mail networks; SLAM [student labor action movement] protests treatment of Tufts' janitors; Freshemn class copes with terrorist attacks; STudents, profs relect on tragedy; Appealing a cappella wins fans; Field hockey team scoreless against Wellesley, holding at 0-1 record in the NESCAC; Football team homes to better last year's 2-6 record, Wesleyan first; Defense is key to football season, led by Dickerson and Mittenthal.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 24; UP029.022.036.00012 (Volume 36)
    UCCPS [University College for Citizenship and Public] shifts focus to Omidyar scholarship; Students avoid downtown Boston amid terrorist threats Saturday; 'Worm' virus attacks networks at Tufts, around nation; How to get rid of your beer gut without actually giving up beer; Difficult return to normalcy after terrorist attacks in US; TCCS [Tufts Computing and Communications Services]; Soccer team hits bump in road [Men's soccer]; Explosive third quarter leads to 32-50 win at Wesleyan; Football opening day proves exciting across NESCAC conferance; Men net first NESCAC victory.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 25; UP029.022.036.00013 (Volume 36)
    Freshmen senators not yet elected, but projects underway; Middle East student group forms; New dorm plans are closer to being finalized; 'Patches for Peace' program hopes to unite students in wake of tragedy; Preparing for war; Beach bound students risk miore than too dark a tan; Learn how to drive a stick shift; Weather conditions thwart runners from peak performance [Men's cross country]; E-mail problems easily fixed; Are janitors really getting the short end of the 'broom'; Don't kill for me; Honoring a murder.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 26; UP029.022.036.00014 (Volume 36)
    Students getting busy signals across campus; Freshmen square off in Hotung; Administration will soon discuss future of vacant dean positions; Government faces tough choices; Freshmen sqaure off in Hotung; Students turn to prescription drugs for recreational use; New first lady settles into Tufts [Adele Bacow]; Women's cross country finishes seventh after two weeks of rest; Volleyball stumbles at Amherst Invitational, drops 8-4 record; Women's field hockey team fals to Colby in fourth straight loss; Sailing team defends title, wins Hood Trophy; Soccer game postponed one day due to rain, will be played today.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 27; UP029.022.036.00015 (Volume 36)
    Tufts celebrates 150th; Mass Electric blamed for yesterday's brief campus power outage; TUPD eases sophomore parking restrictions, allows closer spots; Tutors available online through ARC [academic resource center] webiste; Colloquium addresses America's new war on terrorism; Politcal science professor changes syllabus after attacks; Men's crew to build up for spring sprints, hopes high; Tennis nets victories in first three contests of fall season; 'Heart and intensity' lead soccer team to 3-0 win, record to 4-2 with Gordon defeat [women's soccer]; Jumbos take win over Lord Jeffs; Justice and Vengeance; Islam, a religion of peace; A transfer student's turmoil.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 September 28; UP029.022.036.00016 (Volume 36)
    SCOPE stioll operating sans director [Student of Color Outreach Program]; New associate dean of students is third to hold administrative post in three years; 'Late Lunch' available at Dewick, Carmicheal halls; Today's freshmen elections delayed; Shows of solidarity and support; Volleyball bumps lowly East Nazarene on Tuesday; Women's crew continues stroke of success; Football looking to continue winning streak against Bates College on Saturday; Fresh legs jump-starting soccer team [women's soccer].
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 October 01; UP029.022.036.00017 (Volume 36)
    TCUJ, TCU prez. call for remaining ELBO officer to step down, Teach-in protests military action; [Michele] Shelton resigns from post in TCU Senate; Jerusalem women speak about city; Students react to President Bush's war on terrorism; Internation Club's Unity Bash a success; Making thier mark at their home; Men's soccer ends shutout streak with 2-1 loss to Bates; Jumbos smash their way to second straight football win; Women's soccer blanked by Bates; Field hockey tops Bates 5-4 for first victory of season.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 October 02; UP029.022.036.00018 (Volume 36)
    New block schedule to be tested this month; University places bid to host Billy Joel show; For some, a September without phoen service; At Tufts forum, professors say US likely to undergo recessions soon; Vet school cares for bald eagle; Brandeis gfame to test Tufts field hockey team; Volleyball team wins three of four games at Bates Invitational; Golf places 6 of 11 at NESCAC; I miss Moon; TCU: United we stand; Whose Culture "Freedom"; Three fundamental economic fallacies.
  - Tufts Daily, 2001 October 03; UP029.022.036.00019 (Volume 36)